Onur Kerimov

Frontend Developer

 ullet github.com/onurkerimov ullet linkedin.com/in/onurkerimov ullet onurkerimov@gmail.com ullet Willing to relocate

6+ years of experience in web application development. Passionate about applying strong JS and UI skills to overcome challenges. I've worked in **Adtech**, **Low-code editors**, **Forms**, and **HTML5 games**.

Education

Boğaziçi University

2012 - 2018

BS. Chemical Engineering

Programming skills acquired: C/C++, MATLAB (part of the engineering curriculum), Python (elective) **Graduation project:** Comparing the predictive performances of Lasso, Elastic Net and LARS algorithms

Skills

JavaScript

Fluent in **TypeScript**, with strong fundamentals of **JavaScript**. Used frameworks such as **React**, **Vue**, **Svelte**, and tools such as **Redux**, **GraphQL**, **jQuery**, and **Jest**. Also specialized in **design systems** with accessibility and pixel-perfectness constraints, using visual testing tools such as **Cypress**, **Playwright**, and **Chromatic**.

HTML5 + 3D

Other Tools

Experienced with tools such as **ThreeJS**, **react-three-fiber**, **PIXI**, and the native browser canvas. A basic knowledge of **WebGL** and **WebGPU**.

Next.js, AWS, JIRA, React Native, Tailwind, npm, Webpack, Gulp, Rollup, Electron, Storybook, MaterialUI, Gatsby, Jekyll, Git, Jenkins

Backend + DevOps

Other Skills

Worked with **Node.js** and **Python** backends using tools such as **Express**, **Nest.js**, **tRPC**, and **Flask**. Experienced in maintaining CI/CD pipelines with **Docker** and **GitHub Actions**, and authored internal tooling such as **Babel plugins**, and **codemods**.



Experience

Formsort - New York, NY, USA (Remote)

May 2020 - April 2023

Frontend Developer

Formsort is a specialized content management system for forms, used by enterprises like GoodRx, Calibrate, Candid, Vial, FormHealth. As one of the earliest members of the team, this 3-year era was an invaluable startup-building experience.

- Built key features using TypeScript + React and Python as the main tools.
- Delivered tasks given by the product team, as well as spotted bugs and proposed additional features where necessary.
- Owned large-scale projects that involved working with legacy code, that usually required strategies such as incremental merges, feature flags, versioning, and DB migrations.

- Have been a key contributor to the design system and worked closely with the UI/UX team to deliver pixel-perfect implementations.
- Contributed to a lot of aspects of the codebase, including two performance-critical apps, a marketing website, the CI/CD setup, and the backend.

Adphorus (A Sojern Company) - Istanbul, Turkey

October 2019 - April 2020

Frontend Developer

Adphorus is a Facebook marketing partner platform for enterprises in travel business like Trivago, Kayak, AirFrance, TripAdvisor. It focuses on marketing automation and algorithmic optimization.

- Delivered new features, and fixed bugs using Javascript and React.
- Worked in multi-disciplinary teams, contributed to planning and prioritization processes using tools such as JIRA and Notion.
- Maintained react-date-range, a popular open source project by the company.

Freelance Frontend Developer

July 2018 - October 2019

In this period, I worked on different freelance projects for mutliple clients and employers. It was an highly educative experience and I created open source projects throughout the process.

- Built playable game ads for use on Facebook and other platforms, with mobile-device and file size constraints, using technologies such as PIXI, HTML5 and WebGL.
- Single-handedly conducted a test-driven refactoring process for Graph Commons, migrating the codebase from legacy JavaScript to ES6 modules.
- Built product landing pages for several startup companies.

Projects xoid

2021 - Present

xoid is a framework-agnostic state management library that's designed to make atomic state approachable. It has React, Vue and Svelte integrations, and it unifies concepts like global state, observable streams, and finite state machines in the same, easy to learn API. (https://xoid.dev)

Languages

English (Advanced)
Turkish (Native)
German (Basic)

Interests

Songwriting Hiking Books

Generated on December 25, 2023 · Latest Version: onurkerimov.github.io/cv